Sara Fotros

Software Engineer - Web Developer

Full-stack software engineer, with a background as a professional musician and instructor. My experience as an instructor with a firm basis for problem-solving and communication has taught me to effectively break down problems into simple steps and actively collaborate and learn with others. Another passion of mine is basketball, which I have played at a competitive level.

London, UK +44 7401763373 sarafotros@gmail.com







TECHNICAL PROJECTS









Brings together customers with tradespeople. Users are able to post job requests based on location and service required, create and manage bookings.

- Built a RESTFUL API with Ruby on Rails, with Postgres database
- Implemented Rails Active Storage to attach photo, using Google Cloud
- Utilized JSON Web Tokens and localStorage to store encrypted user information
- Implemented a user interface with React, React Router, and Material UI and JSS for styling
- Incorporated Google Maps API to render an interactive map





E-commerce website for a beauty Salon in order to show/ sell products & services

- Built a RESTFUL API with Ruby on the Rails, with endpoints for users and
- JWT token authentication was used on the frontend and bcrypt on the backend
- Frontend built with JavaScript and React, and React Router and Bootstrap and CSS for styling
- Implemented MVC structure to separate concerns and facilitate development

DeveLooper







Beat Machine for creating and saving drum loops and the ability to change the tempo

- Ruby on the Rails as an API on the backend. SQLite used to designed database
- Written in JavaScript and utilized Tone.JS library to synthesize drum samples
- Designed nested routes to reflect relationships between models
- Used validation and sessions to control users access to resources

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Ruby on Rails **JavaScript** SQLite, **PostgreSQL** React. Redux. Object Oriented Programming HTML, CSS, JSS

EDUCATION

Material UI, Bootstrap

Flatiron School

London ,UK Software Engineering

Bahar School of Management

Tehran-Iran Master of Business Administration in Art

Azad University

Isfahan-Iran Bachelor of science degree in Electrical engineering

EXPERIENCE

Information Systems Engineer (2015 – 2016) Tehran, Iran

- Hands-on experience at early stage telecommunications startup, Mortabet Rayane.
- Responsible for monitoring and maintaining operating systems as well as overseeing telecommunication systems and customer service.
- Evaluated user needs and communicated user feedback and systems functionality to drive product improvements.
- Troubleshooting and resolving approx. 50 daily complicated technical issues, meant that I became skilled at thinking on my feet and problem solving effectively.

Professional Musician (2002-2019), Iran, and UK

- Professional percussionist performing professionally since 2002. Performed at the national level with different ensembles in Iran, and also as part of international commissions in Iran, UK, and globally.
- Recording artist and stage performer featured on numerous audio and visual projects for several popular contemporary and traditional bands including Ajam who were most prominently selected by the BBC World Service as eight acts that represent the contemporary sound of the 'Middle East'. As part of these projects I have performed on radio and television broadcasts in the UK, Sweden, and the USA.
- During my career as a musician, I have achieved various awards for performance excellence including first place in a national level competition held in Kurdistan province of Iran in 2008.

Professional Music Tutor (2002-2019), Iran, and UK

- I have practiced professional tuition at various music institutes, including Sepahan Sina, Navaye Shahrashoob, Rock and Zavieh in Iran.
- I have also provided private tuition in a one-on-one environment for students of varied age and ability in Esfahan, Tehran and London.
- I have formed and managed a percussion ensemble comprising students and colleagues and composed Rhythmic Pieces based on Kurdish, Persian and fusion music for performances in Iran.